pramerica.ie 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy | Pramerica

### PRAMERICA SYSTEMS IRELAND LIMITED

#### PRIVACY STATEMENT & COOKIES POLICY (“PRIVACY STATEMENT”)

#### _INTRODUCTION_

This statement relates to our privacy practices in connection with the website, [www.pramerica.ie](http://www.pramerica.ie/) (the ‘ **Website** ’).

The purpose of this Privacy Statement is to inform you about how we treat your personal information and to explain how your personal information is processed when you use our Website. As a result, you will be able to provide consent to the processing of your personal information in a free and informed way in the sections of the Website in which you are asked to provide personal information. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such, we have no control over the contents of those sites or resources.

#### _WHO WE ARE_

This Website is operated by Pramerica Systems Ireland Limited, a company incorporated and registered in Ireland with company registration number 319900 with its registered office at 6th Floor, South Bank House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (“ **Pramerica Ireland** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”). Please use the contact information provided at the end of this statement if you have any complaints or queries regarding this statement and your personal information we may hold.

#### _GENERAL STATEMENT_

We fully respect your right to privacy and will not collect personal information about you on this Website without your permission. Any personal information which you volunteer to us will be treated with high standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (‘ **DPA** ’).

#### _IMPORTANT NOTICE_

The terms governing the general use of our Website are set out in our  User Agreement.. By using this Website you are deemed to fully accept this Privacy Statement and Cookies Policy and our  User Agreement. If you do not agree with the terms of our Privacy Statement, Cookies Policy and User Agreement you should not use this Website.

#### _INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU_

#### _TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED_

We retain two types of information:

  1. **“Personal Data”.** This is data that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you and may include your first name, surname, email address and telephone number.  Such information is only collected from you if you **voluntarily** submit it to us, for example, by using the Contact Us pages or the Recruitment Forms on the Website or by emailing us directly.
  2. **“Non-Personal Data”.** Like most websites, we gather statistical and other analytical information collected on an aggregate basis of all visitors to our Website.  This Non-Personal Data comprises information that cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information regarding, for example, user IP addresses where they have been clipped or anonymised, browser types and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our Website.

#### _PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE HOLD YOUR INFORMATION_

**Personal Data**

We will process any Personal Data you provide to us for the following purposes:

  * to respond to any comments or Recruitment Application you submit to us and to communicate with you in relation to our company and its services. Please note that Pramerica uses a third party to process Recruitment Applications and hold personal data on record.;
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * to contact you in relation to our newsletters, events or publications (subject to any preferences you have expressed regarding such communications).

**Non-Personal Data**

We use the Non-Personal Data gathered from visitors to our Website in an aggregate form to:

  * gain a better understanding of where our visitors come from and what technology is used to access the Website;
  * learn more about the number of visitors to the Website, traffic patterns and visitor behaviours on our Site; and
  * help us improve design and navigation of the Website and ensure content is relevant and useful to visitors.

Please note we do not use Personal Data for targeted advertising or behavioural advertising.

#### _COOKIES_

We may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer.  Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the website.  Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.  They help us learn more about visitor patterns and behaviours on our Website and this is used to continually improve and develop our Website. Some of the cookies we use are essential for the Website to operate.

You may block cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the settings of all or some cookies.

If you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our Website.  Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our Website.

**Who drops cookies when I use the website?**

Many of the cookies dropped when you use our Website are “first party cookies” (meaning cookies placed and read by us directly).

A number of our third party partners may also drop cookies when you use our Website. These are specialist “third party cookies”, they are not set by us but are rather set by companies such as Google for website analytics purposes with our permission. Please read our third party partners’ privacy policies to ensure that you are comfortable with the manner in which they use cookies:

**What types of cookies are used on the Website?**

We use both “session” and “persistent” cookies.

A session cookie is used to identify a particular visit to our Website. These cookies expire after a short time, or when you close your web browser after using our Website.

A persistent cookie will remain on your devices for a set period of time specified in the cookie. We use these cookies where we need to identify you over a longer period of time.

**Why are cookies used?  **

We use cookies for the following purposes:

**Analytics**  – we use cookies to learn how you, and other users, use our Website and how well it performs. This enables us to identify errors, learn how our Website performs, and improve and develop our Website over time.

**Website Optimization** – we use cookies to improve the operation and presentation of our Website.

#### _WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA_

The data that we collect from you may be stored on site at our Letterkenny, Co. Donegal, Ireland location(s) or be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your Personal Data, you agree to this transfer, storing and/or processing. We will take steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

#### _DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION_

Except as otherwise indicated in this Privacy Statement any Personal Data  which you provide us with is not made available to any third parties unless you give your prior consent to us by way of email, and is used by us only in line with the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement. Notwithstanding the foregoing, where appropriate, Personal Data may be processed by our service providers in which case we will take steps to ensure that the processing complies with applicable data protection and confidentiality laws, including the DPA. We may consider it necessary to disclose Personal Data  without your consent or without consulting you, when we believe that it is appropriate to comply with our legal obligations and/or a Court Order, to cooperate with any law enforcement agencies, to enforce this Privacy Statement, our User Agreement, our Terms and Conditions or other legal rights, to protect the security of the Website, to protect the security and safety of others, to prevent fraud, or otherwise to protect our legitimate interests and/or the legitimate interests of other users. We may also transfer your personal data on the sale, transfer or reorganisation of our business.

We may provide Non-Personal Data to third parties, where such information is combined with similar information of other users of our Website.  For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit our Website, the demographic breakdown of our community users of our Website or the activities that visitors to our Website engage in while on our Website.  The third parties to whom we may provide this information may include web developers, server providers, our affiliates, providers of advertising services (including website tracking services), commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties.

#### _NEWSLETTERS AND UPDATES_

If you subscribe to our newsletter or any other e-mail updates, by submitting your e-mail address through a subscribe facility on the Website, and you wish to opt-out of receiving these communications, please access the “Unsubscribe” link that is available on all such emails. If you have any difficulty unsubscribing please contact us using the contact information provided at the end of this Privacy Statement.

#### _UPDATING, VERIFYING, DELETING PERSONAL DATA_

You may inform us of any changes in your Personal Data, and in accordance with our obligations under the DPA.  If you discover that we hold inaccurate information about you, you can request us to correct that information for free. These requests must be in writing and sent to us at our mailing address provided below, or e-mail us at [info@www.pramerica.ie](mailto:info@www.pramerica.ie).

In certain circumstances you may also request that data which you have supplied via the Website be deleted. We will comply within 40 calendar days of the receipt of such a request.  We aim to ensure that all data is accurate, complete and up to date in accordance with the principles set out in the DPA.

#### _RIGHT OF ACCESS_

Further, you have a right to be given a copy of your Personal Data we have in our possession. On request, we can supply copies of your Personal Data which you may have supplied via the Website or otherwise. If you wish to obtain such copies, you must write to us at our mailing address provided below, or e-mail us at [info@www.pramerica.ie](mailto:info@www.pramerica.ie). You should include any personal identifiers which you supplied earlier via the Website or otherwise (e.g. username, e-mail address). We will also require your full name and residential address in those circumstances. We reserve the right to charge a statutory fee, as permitted under the DPA.We will comply within  40 calendar days of the receipt of such a request.

#### _SOCIAL MEDIA_

Any content we publish using social media channels is subject to separate terms and conditions governing the particular channel. Should you choose to communicate with us or to follow us on social media it is up to you to choose your preferred profile settings.

#### _CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT_

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Statement at any time to reflect changes in the law, our data collection and use practices, the features of our Website, or advances in technology. Please check this page periodically for changes. If we make any changes to this Privacy Statement, we will post the updated Privacy Statement here and you will be notified of such change upon entering the Website following any change. Please review the changes carefully. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to this policy will mean you consent to and accept those changes. If you do not consent to such changes you should immediately stop using the Website.

#### _CONTACTING US_

If you have any questions, requests or complaints regarding this Privacy Statement please contact us using the following information:  
**Web:** [www.pramerica.ie](http://www.pramerica.ie/)  
**Email:** [info@www.pramerica.ie](mailto:info@www.pramerica.ie)  
**Mailing Address:**  
Letterkenny Office Park,  
Windyhall,  
Letterkenny, Co. Donegal,  
Ireland

This statement was last modified August 2016.
